Grammar, in a nutshell, even in complex sentences, stress the noun unless there's
contrast. Everything you ever wanted to know about grammar but were afraid to use.
English is a chronological language. We just love to know when something happened,
and this is indicated by the range and depth of our verb tenses. I had already
seen it by the time she brought it in. As you probably learned in your grammar
studies, the past perfect is an action in the past before a separate action in the
past. Phew! Not all languages do this. For example, Japanese is fairly casual about
when things happened, but being a hierarchical language, it's very important
to know what relationship the two people involved had. A high-level person with a
low-level one, two peers, a man and a woman, all these things show up in
Japanese grammar. Grammatically speaking, English is democratic. The confusing part
is that in English, the verb tenses are very important, but instead of putting
them up on the peaks of a sentence, we throw them all deep down in the valleys.
Therefore, two sentences with strong intonations, such as dogs eat bones and
the dogs will have eaten the bones, sound amazingly similar. Why? Because it takes
the same amount of time to say both sentences since they have the same number
of stresses. The three original words and the rhythm stay the same in these
sentences, but the meaning changes as you add more stressed words. Articles and verb
tense changes are usually not stressed. Now, let's see how this works in the
exercises that follow.